

I'm a full-stack designer with a passion for clean, approachable, and robust designs. I've managed all aspects of design projects through initial strategy and ideation, sketches and wireframes, pixel-perfect comps, and partnering with engineers to deliver great user experiences.

Experience



Senior Principal Designer @ Dell Technologies

2020 - present

- Design lead for Dell's next generation cloud services platform which will provide key capabilities required for the transformation of Dell's Managed Services business.
- Design lead for a new website integrating multiple services.



Microsoft

14 years

Senior Design Lead

2013 - 2020

- Designed and worked with a multi-disciplinary team to deliver a new Azure DevOps app for the GitHub marketplace. While there were challenging constraints, customer acquisition improved more than expected and helped drive Azure attach revenue.
- Led the design of a YAML-based pipeline editing experience built on the Monaco editor and fully integrated into Azure DevOps.
- Contributed to a full redesign of Azure Pipelines, adopting and contributing to a new design system as part of the process. Among the challenges were a radical rework of the underlying architecture and providing a migration path. Usability and acceptance testing confirmed improved customer satisfaction and adoption rates.

Senior Program Manager @ Microsoft

2006 - 2012

- Drove the delivery of a new Azure-hosted on-demand build automation service.
 Provided training to the field and helped customers successfully transition.
- Became an expert on continuous integration and delivery and articulated how we could succeed in that space by creating a feature roadmap. Evangelized those plans with customers and partners to drive that roadmap to fruition.
- Became an expert on Git and engaged with top customers to help design and deliver support for the distributed version control system in the Visual Studio and Web clients.



Founder @ Brilliant Labs

2003 - 2006

I created BrilliantPhoto, a digital photo management application downloaded by over 70K users worldwide. Written in C++, the product included a broad set of media management and image processing features and received top ratings from C-NET. In the year following its introduction, BrilliantPhoto had over 70,000 installs.



CTO, Information Technology Solutions @ Intuit

2000 - 2003

As the CTO for Blue Ocean Software (acquired by Intuit in 2002), I was responsible for all aspects of product development, overseeing a staff of 30 (grown from 5). I formalized the product development lifecycle, built partnerships with localization, self-service, remote control, and software distribution vendors. I established a steering committee made up of our top enterprise customers to facilitate communication and gather feedback.

Skills

Product Design, Web Design, UI Design, UX Design, Information Architecture, Design Systems, Interaction Design, Management, DevOps, Azure, Figma, Git, GitHub

Education

Bachelor of Arts, Honors University of Virginia Charlottesville, VA

Get in touch!

jaime@jflamb.com • +1 (919) 475-7244